when one okay welcome everyone to
another wasabi research club meeting
today we're talking about a 2006 paper
called anonymity loves company usability
in the network effects this paper is by
Dingell dine and Mathewson and you can
find all the papers that we read on our
website the link is just below our
github excuse me just to remind everyone
where we are in the last few weeks we
were talking about coin shuffle + + +
cash Fusion and I've decided to call
this meeting you know sort of principles
in privacy or perhaps principles and
privacy in anonymity networks because I
think it's very appropriate to what
we're doing and next week's research
club meeting will be decided by the end
of this meeting you can find everything
on the github just a reminder two weeks
ago and last week we talked about cash
Fusion talked about doing coin joins
with arbitrary numbers of inputs and
outputs where users all submit inputs
outputs and blanks and through the magic
of home Orphic encryption homework like
Peter Peterson commitments we can
guarantee that no one is getting more
money than they put in and we have all
users verifying other users to make sure
that no one cheated last week we asked
the question is this really private is
it secure can someone break this method
of obfuscated inputs and outputs and
there was a claim being made in our
discussion that due to the Bell member
and the subset-sum problem you are
secure given enough users who possess a
large enough set of inputs and outputs
within a particular range of values
because the bail number is quite large
in those cases and the knapsack problem
is computationally difficult to solve
please see videos on YouTube for
interesting debate that ensued after
this discussion so yes so the question
posed by this paper that we're reading
today is how should we think about
building using privacy tools in
anonymity networks when I say anonymity
networks I mean something like tour or
jab or mixed minion Mixmaster or an art
we care about in these calls is coin
joint an eminent work relies on getting
anonymity from hiding among other users
and from this idea we get the anonymity
set which is the concept that you are as
anonymous as the number of people that
are acting and behaving like you in this
anonymity Network so the author
encourages us through a thought
experiment to consider something this
sort imagine you have an email you want
to set and you have two options for
email encryption on your left is a
little a tiny padlock it's a light
crypto security encryption scheme for
your email and on the right is a big
lock it's a heavy crypto encryption
scheme so you have to ask yourself Who
am I going to use the heavy duty
encryption or the lightweight encryption
the obvious thing is to say oh I'll just
use the the best possible encryption
scheme that there is out there however
what this fails to consider is that
email encryption isn't a one-person
endeavor it's something you do with
other participants and other
participants might not use the same
email encryption scheme that you use but
not just that even if you do use a
particular email encryption
if they use the scheme you are using
orally your privacy is hurt because the
anime community the anonymity network is
weakened by bad participants who don't
know what they're doing and if you are
really super knowledgeable about using
email encryption and there's only ten
other people in the whole world that are
aware of this then you have another
problem which is that are you really
hidden in this network so we're going to
talk about some principles in anonymity
network so insecure so these are just
some things that were brought up by the
author insecure modes of operation are
bound to be used unknowingly in those
modes so if you have some encryption
schemes some sort of privacy scheming
and anonymity network insecure modes of
operation are big red flag optional
security typically get turned off and
users forget to turn them back on ever
again the example that's given here is
browser cookies so a lot of people click
no when a site asks for cookies but then
later will look yes and they'll never go
back to cookie no so from then on
they're always giving their personal
information to sites that the isn't
badly labeled us which is another
problem and this is where a user has the
ability to turn off something that
secures their privacy and doesn't
realize that they're they're really
harming their privacy because they see a
switch and it's not properly labeled as
a dangerous off switch so they they
trigger it and they don't realize that
they've heard their privacy and what's
worse is that someone could convince
that users do that as a social
engineering attack inconvenience
security often ends up being tossed
aside for more convenient but less
secure methods of operation so people
don't people don't want to behave in a
convenient way so they'll pick the more
convenient way which is often hurts that
false sense of security is a big problem
wearing
wrongfully thinks that what they're
doing is securing private when what
they're doing is not secured private and
then bad mental models encourage users
to behave in in the wrong way and don't
accurately allow the user to appreciate
how private or secure their behavior is
so usability is more important for
privacy this is the claim the author is
making so when more users join the
network existing users benefit this is
the case with every anonymity Network
that we're talking about and encryption
is different than an intimidating and
eliminated network you can excuse me
with encryption you can encrypt your own
files on your own computer with any
encryption scheme that you want you
could pick the strongest encryption
scheme that's fine but when you're in an
anonymity network you depend on your
peers to be anonymous so when we talk to
so the example here is it is going to be
tor but I just want to remind you that
coin shuffle use the same idea I will
just show the analogy if you recall all
these users have their outputs and they
want to do a coin joint but they have
these equal outputs that must be
anonymous and so what they do is they
onion encrypt their outputs and then run
them through a network of their peers
and the final result is a set of outputs
that no one knows where the outputs came
from only orange knows is his or her own
output and yellow knows his or her own
output but yellow doesn't know anyone
else is outputting so everyone is
anonymous against everyone else and no
one knows anyone else's outputs and tor
is that they you know exactly the same
idea in this case the peers are tor
nodes and here red wants to send a
packet maybe to a website you know pick
paint a website and so he or she onion
encrypts through the network you know at
each layer the the at each step one
layer is removed and sent the cross at
any point you know someone like
has no idea this has come from read at
each point it's just one person passing
to the next until finally purple will
reach out to the website on behalf of
red without even knowledge that the red
is the person that said the information
so toresen anonymity network if you
can't break the encryption of tor which
once we assume you can't then really
what it looks like it's just this big
black box where users are you know
entering the network and they're doing
all sorts of activity and all you see is
activity coming in and coming out but
you don't know how to cut which person
to which other person and so the first
problem is that if only one person is
using tor it's trivial to see to link
information going out of to out of the
Tor network and information coming into
the Tor network another problem is that
if everyone is speaking Yiddish and
doing things in a very Western English
way so for example you know you know
writing in English accessing English
websites maybe only awake at certain
times of the day
then someone here for example who's
Hungarian speaking Hungarian will be
easily G anonymize by the fact that
they're the only person that that's
doing that so usability versus security
is a big problem
you have to ask you know which are
you're gonna take are you going to pick
the slow high latency system or the fast
low latency system which are you going
to pick well supposing that the high
latency slow system is way way better
but nobody is using it it ends up being
the case that even though you know it's
more secure it's better to use the
faster Network where more people are
currently using it and a big thing that
the the author now
Clay's is that easier against for max
this this this section is for max yes so
I'm gonna really hold it in and not say
anything about Mesabi even though the
tone of my voice should hit strongly
that this is talking about us but the
author argues against options right so
designers are faced with security
decisions they leave it to the user
because designers don't necessarily know
what the right thing to do the protocol
designer is leaving to the implementers
the implementers leave it also to the
users and what ends up happening users
are the least able to make decisions for
themselves so if you're asking a user
hey you go ahead you decide abs or to
fish which which is your preferred
symmetric encryption scheme unless you
know what is what symmetric encryption
schemes look like and you know the
difference between those two models you
are not the right person to answer that
question alkanes make the code very hard
to audit because the configuration of a
particular software is exponentially
grows with them with more option that
you give it so if you give you know one
option over here option a and one option
over here
option B then whether or not option A is
on or off and whether or not a PB is on
or off give you four options and then
you know this is clearly girls
exponentially users with uncommon
preferences are singled out this is a
very interesting one so you give people
tons of options now they select you know
out of the 14 options you give them they
select seven of them that is already way
very unlikely to match with someone else
and the default option usually prevails
for casual users and so it should
prevail for experienced users as well
this is a pretty big argument that's
being made by the author but I think
it's it's very convincing so one case
study was the mixed minion and the mind
case study so mixed minion is and
an email anonymity Network and mine is
the multi-purpose internet mail
extension it's just a flag that tells
you the the format of the content of an
email the problem is that every email
service service uses a distinct mind and
the what that means is that if if two
people are using one email service and
everyone else uses a different one you
can clearly link those two email
services to each other so one one
thought you might have is well okay why
don't we just limit everyone who uses
our mix minion software to one format
but the others talked about how if you
if you limit to one format all of a
sudden you don't let users send Word
documents you don't let users send PDF
documents you don't let users do all of
these things so what's gonna happen is
the user is gonna figure out a way to
overcome this problem by by making by
doing the wrong thing essentially in
terms of privacy and by hurting their
privacy while thinking they're still
doing good for their privacy and further
it will end up being the case that users
simply leave the port O'Call
altogether because you didn't give them
enough options so in the end and I was
surprised to read this the the middle
ground the the best case for privacy was
to allow users to behave in a diverse
way but more than clearly about certain
choices okay tor installation tor is
what's used by only cool nerds on unique
systems and then as you new users
started to join and used for there was a
need to quickly onboard them without a
lot of a lot of explanation what
beginners did not understand DNS issues
so what happened is they didn't realize
that tor wouldn't help at all if you are
pinging a website or the clear net for a
lookup table of the site that you're
looking to access so you need us socks5
proxy or whatever it is and beginners
that understand this so what kind of
solution is could could we do for these
these users who essentially we're
getting no privacy
by doing this well okay the first thing
was improve documentation turns out that
didn't help it only helped users who
read it and all the illusions that
didn't read it just continue to make
make big privacy blunders the next thing
was give a warning message this only
created more confusion you know you
would say to them hey you're you know by
a by using tor without a Sox by proxy
your dns is really leaked to the blah
blah the user would just be completely
confused about what was going on finally
the the working solution was an error
message that pointed to the
documentation which told you sir what to
do okay so this is where I ran out of
time cuz I'm a busy man but I take
responsibility so we'll continue talking
about the paper but I don't have any
more slides so we'll just leave it to
discussion Thank You Arif I think this
paper was very different from from the
previous sessions because it was very
unique in a sense that kind of a
philosophical paper but in a research
paper philosophy capice in a research
paper so that said that's why I don't
have much comments on it but I have
something I have one two three four five
questions for the author who is not with
us but I have three more topics to
discuss and and this might be a bit
redundant because of we've talked about
it but let's let's see the very first
thing I just I just want to I just want
to to quote something that another area
where human factors are critical in
privacy he's bootstrapping new systems
and this resonates with me a lot because
in wasabi the other Hebrew bootstrap
this thing was quite huge issue back
then
it's somehow all worked out yeah what
what what do you guys have yeah if I
remember the early days where we had the
anonymity set of five for wasabi meat
sauce and of course it did not give you
much privacy at all but still you know
enthusiasts could use it knowing that
they did not get much privacy but but
knowing the potential that it has right
and that it's at least you know better
than nothing even if you do small realms
it's it's still better than nothing I
didn't not to encourage one at all so
that was the reason why I used it right
first if it was the only workable
solution so there was no other option
for me as an enthusiast and second III I
saw the potential of what this can be
and that if I help bootstrap the system
now that later at a point in time when
others start using this you know but I
can have a better tool yeah I remember
finding out about wasabi maybe because
of Max's videos and all of his
enthusiasm about what hobby wallet and
that kind of like drove me into looking
it up and yeah I was definitely a little
surprised that it wasn't that difficult
that I first thought but yeah I mean
there's a lot of confusing little words
or words that people use when talking
about wasabi wallet and the coin joints
in itself so I think that's a big issue
that it might scare people off just
because they don't know what to expect
it's interesting isn't it we have a
philosophical paper and because of the
lack of of technical depth in it but
it's very good huge big picture document
but because of the lack of technical
things we are already putting on to
applying it to to the best-known system
that we know about
she's facade
maybe this conversation is gonna be
about fasabi yeah I think that we should
talk about what something because
there's no way to it's interesting way
to nest this conversation into something
that we can all understand really well
so let me start by saying this this
paper made me feel like I'm like I was
right about something and wrong about
something
from the past so one thing I was right
about that more at least is this paper
argues that I was right about is the
idea that if we can we should make the
way that wasabi works very very simple
to the point where you know to explain
to a user what they're gonna expect out
of Mesabi it should be it should be very
simple and I should stay constant and
the same so it seems like this paper
would argue for that where I was wrong
is is the idea of giving people a lot of
options so allowing people you know for
example I was very happy with the custom
fee and I wasn't happening before that
when there wasn't a custom fee but
having read this paper I actually am of
the belief that there should only be
three options for a fee and if we really
care about what we were doing we should
accept the fact that even though you
don't get your perfect exact correct fee
that you think is right it's still
better for everyone else and I think
that's something we should we should do
across the board for all features you
know the crimper giving it up because
that was exactly what came to my mind to
the issue of the fee like that
personally love setting the custom fees
exactly how I like it but after reading
this paper that's very stupid to do you
know you should just go with Bitcoin
course Marty estimation and do the
default that everyone else uses that
leads to much less followed
fingerprinting but you know it also
comes with the other point in the paper
that although although they're having
too many options
an issue if you don't have many options
then people will not use it right the
power user who insists on having the
custom fees evil evil you know then no
longer used for sabe thus decreasing the
network effect so I think what we have
right now is a decent compromise where
you know at least the average user has
only the fee slider with Bitcoin core
estimation but then in these settings an
advanced user can activate the custom
fee and do what he wants right so I
think that is good but I would know much
more a much more go into that direction
where I would suggest to every user to
always go with Bitcoin core unless it is
it is some case but it really is
military yeah I agree with that what I
really liked was was the idea of having
error messages point to documentation
because I know we have excellent
documentation and we're very proud of it
but right now the problem is that most
users don't read it and the biggest plus
that I see from the documentation is
that yahia is really good at referencing
documentation when answering questions
to people on on reddit so he's doing
exactly what the paper recommends which
is when someone asks a question you just
point exactly in the documentation where
it is but if we could have altering
settings like with an error message that
points to documentation so you know if I
turn off tour actually say error you've
turned off tour here's the documentation
where it explains why tour protects your
privacy we should somehow be yeah I've
been thinking about this too because
there is a bullet I think it's called
exodus' and people were saying very good
things about it that it it has the
documentation in the wallet itself and
that gives them a lot of confidence and
I was thinking about it's it's a lot to
but how do you you know how do you solve
this technical challenge
in a different way because they'll be
waste to add the documentation into
Vasavi and and it's kind of like that
duplicating everything but how do you
solve it without duplicating that's a
good question
or is the is the system stable enough so
we could have sufficient documentation
or is the system is is going to change
that much that it just doesn't work
building the documentation into Vasavi
you know I think documentation in wasabi
is exactly right one thing I thought
about reading this paper is about mental
models and to me it's like every time I
should I open wasabi it should have ten
like where were five screens beautiful
graphic screens like six 102 Bitcoin
with his graphic designs that I can skip
if I want to like a big skip button
right below but every time you go into
wasabi you just feel like hey this is
what you're doing this is what it looks
like this is you know just some good
mental models for users and having
documentation and these mental models in
wasabi without them having to go to a
website or reddit or daughter github I
think that would be a pretty big plus
yeah yes I agree Aviv here it
it's I think a two-fold approach right
one is to have such a starting guide to
get every user on the on the same in on
the same starting point and and that is
definitely awesome and then further it
would be for these advanced things like
Evita as you mentioned when you turn off
tour all right these things were many
edge cases there's thousands of them in
the wallet right where then one pop-up
notification comes that says this is
wrong
danger be careful here is explained why
right so I think a combination of both
is what might be useful against
documentation in the wallet I'm just
bringing up that there are other issues
here which is the technical death that
everything of
has to be created in we'd be the
documentation itself and if you want to
change something then you have to update
the documentation it's like it's like
double work and it might work when when
the product doesn't really want to
change that much anymore oh it's like
it's like new languages it's like having
your software in many different
languages is awesome except that you
won't be able to change it anymore and
without without fixing every single
language you know that is the real issue
here I mean software ones is is soft
right hardware is hard
it doesn't change software is soft it
Taurus changes any way anymore on this
you know I think one especially
regarding options that is very
applicable to wasabi it's the question
of manual or automatic coin selection
right of course it's in my opinion one
of the best features of wasabi to have
the manual coin selection because
there's allows users who know what
they're doing to use this to a great
extent but of course this also means
that anyone who does not know what
they're doing with just a vast majority
of all users to shoot themselves in the
foot and to [__] up right so where where
do we stand here can we or they even
have the technical capacity to having a
same automatic coin selection algorithm
that actually works for anyone right yes
I think it's already possible but it's a
lot of work and thinking and how do you
do the levers but maybe that's
definitely the goal right to get rid of
the coins but it's not going to happen
within five to ten years maybe because
it's just
in grayned but but on the other hand
moving into the direction of of
automatic coin selection by grouping
coins it's it's like semi-automatic that
that would that would make sense
more sense than just getting rid of the
coins all together or they're just moved
slowly into that direction like all the
the red all the green coins and there is
not really much of a difference between
them so they could be grouped into one
role for example actually I would point
out that there is a difference between
green coins if they're they come from
two separate instances of mixing as an
example if I mix some coins to two weeks
ago and I mixed some coins yesterday
those green coins are coming from
different times so an optimal coin
selection would actually pick coins from
across both because that would really be
confusing to in terms of linking which
which user does on yeah maybe not but
there are exactly the same yes they are
not exactly the same but for all intents
and purposes for for all the threat
models they could be considered the same
yes again right and in the issue that
comes up here is that as long as we rely
on manual coin selection we again has
user bias on on which option is being
chosen right and and that can lead to to
again finger printing off individual
users depending on how they select the
coins and so this is indeed a very very
pressing issue I don't agree with that
until you give me an example
hmm we think well specifically for coin
selection you're talking about money own
selection now yes I know for example
what what what avi said that if you have
two different you know clusters of mixed
coins right they're mixed but they're
still from different sessions of mixing
now if one user all the time selects for
one transaction only those coins within
one session and another user selects
coins from that span across sessions you
know that that might already be be from
some thread model user doesn't even know
that there are sessions even I'm not
sure four sessions mean in this context
different rounds maybe but but as far as
I understood Aviv went down on that
ultrabeat hole and then ended up nowhere
because it did not really really made
that much sense is that correct
assertion of the situation sorry I went
down with this these two sessions coins
thing it means having collections from
two different sessions yes yeah so the
reason why I think it would make some
sense is because you know if you have if
you receive let's just a simple example
you received one Bitcoin twice so once a
month ago once a week ago and you have
ten coins from both if you if you need
to send someone one Bitcoin it would be
better for you to send a few coins from
the
we could go in a few coins from the
month ago why because it so generally
you don't want to send all the coins
from a mix right you don't want to see
like if you if you if you mixed coins
and I have 20 coins you don't send all
of those 20 together
so how come because you you know you
sort of you've entered at one point in
the network you've exited another point
and the amounts are similar so there's a
higher degree of link ability so what
happens is is if you pointed to
different times you measured right now
there's a I think this is my version I
think I your intuition is right which is
that you know if you are mixing one
after another then those coins might be
more likely to to belong to the same
cluster right this is your intuition and
and and this is somewhat right what what
you're missing there is that merging
together coins actually exposes that
link hundred percent so it's you don't
expose more than you are addicts but you
know what I mean
so the information that sorry merging
coins links a hundred percent yeah yeah
how's that you put two coins into the
same transaction so that must come from
the same person right okay
block chain analysis heuristics 101
Kashyap holistic that's okay but
blocking analysis will we'll look at
those those two coins and say
okay one point is from but we can go one
point is to a month ago now we need to
find a user that used wasabi a month ago
and a week ago and that could be any
user like that there's a lot of users
there and they they they don't have a
good upper balance because the user only
selected one coin from each it's instead
of two coins from the same place why
would okay III them so so it might be in
my example of a person who received one
coin one Bitcoin a month ago one bit
when we go he has 20 coins in total
right 10 from a week ago 10 from a month
ago and I'm saying if you want to send
someone one Bitcoin it's better that you
send five coins from a week ago and five
points from a month ago then ten coins
from a week ago right because five coins
from a week ago there's a lot of people
that that mixed and had five coins from
a week ago in five coins from a month
ago there's a lot of people that had
five points from a month ago so that's
where my intuition comes from as opposed
to ten coins which is which is now
duction you know obvious that intuition
might be right but i would say it
depends very much on the other users
writer quoting here the paper chapter
ten uses safety relies on them behaving
like the others users but how can they
predict how other users behave right and
that's exactly the issue if there are if
there are more people who have ten coins
from this week compared to users that
have five coins from this week five
coins from last month then you might
actually be better to send the ten
points from this week rather than the
size and the size because there are more
users who have ten coins from this week
so so although your intuition might be
correct it very much depends on other
users and how do we know how would their
coin situation is we don't feel ok
that's a good that's a very good point
yes I don't also I don't agree with that
I'll be with that inside because you are
dachshund or another tenant Bitcoin you
TXO for no reason I mean I do kinda
understand what you mean by that
confusing the assignment analysis and
mixing up another UT echo from different
time or different rounds but I don't
know you would have to go on and mix
that then Bitcoin UT EXO again anyway so
I'm not sure if that's the most
convenient thing for the user to do I'm
not sure but my intuition would be to
disagree regarding this paper just he's
really really instructive that we're
talking about these UTX of coin
selections those even if the intuition
would be hundred percent correct there
is still the the thing that we learned
last week that it's kind of
computationally infeasible to to look at
his links especially if you are talking
with probabilities and and this brings
back brings us back to the paper that is
is this procrastination and the user
experience shouldn't be more important
than some some really weak intuition on
privacy you know and this is right we
here to write of course that there might
be you know something to be figured out
on how precisely to to this coin
selection and then how to do it right
after all I think the the this is a
comparatively a marginal gain of privacy
right some better private a time
correlation protection or whatever but
comparing that to a user interface that
is much more intuitive
where more users will use it or the
anonymity set as a whole grows that will
give I would say much more privacy of
course it's a different strategy I agree
with max actually I think there are way
bigger problems and bigger gains we can
make them quite selection I was just
thinking out loud so I'm happy to
concede that the Quinn selection doesn't
matter that much or at least me if I
want if you wouldn't think about this at
another time okay new topic I am reading
from the paper reboot ability is an
anonymity issue for two reasons first it
impacts the sustainability of the
network a network that's always about to
be shut down has difficulty attracting
and keeping users so it's anonymity set
suffers second a disreputable network
attracts the attention of powerful
attackers who may not mind revealing the
identities of all of the users to
uncover a few bad ones now I was
watching the tour developers talk
yesterday and he was talking about Silk
Road that when Silk Road was shut down
I'm not sure which agency um but some
some American US agency went to him and
told him that 90% of the tor traffic
just disappear because ciick road was
shut down and he was like oh really
went home and and look at the stuff that
what was going on and it turned out that
that was a lie so that's why
transparency is kind of important in
anonymity systems because
other words or is just say any
statistics that they come up with out of
nowhere and just just makes make false
accusations
so repeatability what's your thoughts on
that yes I think that that's quite a
good insight right because again the
reputation will lead users to trust or
not trust the software with their
privacy and then of course the more the
more users trust a specific software
were tooled in general was to be used to
protect their privacy the higher the
anonymity sent us the higher the privacy
right so if you have some shady provider
you know claiming that he gives privacy
but not nobody really believing him then
of course nobody will use him and duster
will actually not be any privacy
compared to if you have a provider that
is very transparent and very open and
very educated then this this will leave
more users to to trust that this is the
right tool to use and thus providing a
higher anonymity said yeah sorry the big
thing with the paper that I took away is
how important it is to help the least
knowledgeable users you know how
critical they are and because if you
think of a lot of people that come into
the Bitcoin space and that are you know
not super tech oriented don't know don't
know a lot a lot of those people are not
you know the malicious or nefarious so
if they decide not to use wasabi then
wasabi is only used by two groups
criminals and people who are smart and
appreciate privacy and have the ability
to do that but but we have to have you
know everyday people who don't even know
very much apart from that is secure in
private who are using it without without
flaw we're very much a creed and that
was funnily enough my main motivation of
doing the educational videos at first
because I realized that the tool is [__]
if only five people use it
if I want privacy myself I better
educate others how to use it
alright so the very last topic I have
for today and I'm going to just just
give this question out and let you guys
think about it and I'm not sure I'm
going to contribute much or the
conversation from here on just wait for
some awkward moment and and then discuss
the next next meetings a schedule of
what what we should do so after reading
this paper should I put it you know this
paper is about usability more important
than then technical hardness and it's
quiet apparent that possibly was from
the very beginning was going for
anonymity like in the hardest sense that
could be humanly achieved on Bitcoin and
compare it to something like dark wallet
yeah probably dark wallet was the purest
idea of usability there that it was
doing to off to Cohen joins if you wanna
send money somewhere then you register
this sand and whenever there is another
person who wants to send you're gonna
send together that that was dark wallet
and maybe we are in the wrong path with
Vasavi against trying to it ultimate
privacy but maybe just two of two coin
joints would do much more for Bitcoin
privacy than this
I think Adam here you're on somewhat of
a track here but I think it can still be
combined both if you have only the dark
wallet concept very usable but only two
of two coins
then it although it might provide a
large anonymity set of a total number of
users before any given user it does not
provide much privacy at all those so of
course what I would like to have is a
bit of both I do have 50 anonymity set
coin joints that are very easy one-click
function that just work so of course
that would be perfect to have a good
mathematically sound privacy protocols
that are very easy to use I study the
motion with max the payment explicitly
says if you use an unsecure protocol it
doesn't matter how easy to use it is
it's not secure it's not private
so to of to go enjoy this is not a
two-person Quinten is not - it is not
secure I would say five person point
join it's not secure but then again I
get attacked on Twitter as Maxted
earlier today yeah so I want to bring up
one point that that shows how the wasabi
philosophy is slightly divergent from
the philosophy of this paper and that
has to do with the fee that we charge
for our users
so wasabi charges users based on the
anonymity set this is a an incredibly
fair thing to do because it's
proportional to how much try to see you
are getting right you can paying the
portion along price you're getting and
that seems incredibly fair so if you're
getting not a lot of privacy you're not
you're not paying as much but the result
is twofold as a problem the first
problem is that users never know how
much it costs and the second quite
ironically quite funny is that as soon
as one person behaves poorly and gets D
anonymized people will go on Twitter and
say oh you charged for 80 anonymity set
but you're getting only 50 so you're
being ripped off which is something that
we're not in control of so I just want
people what
their thoughts because I think that pain
/ anonymity set is the correct your way
to do it from a practical standpoint
users simply don't know what's going on
most users don't know what they're gonna
expect to pay and and are confused that
doesn't need a very good point of these
that you bring up and maybe to put this
a bit more into the light of in context
of the paper the paper describes these
costs for privacy mainly in terms of
latency I said that if you want to use a
more private system you have to pay with
your time right and this might also then
come to it you know you can configure it
how long do you want to wait until tor
go to your website or whatever and
having a user option to do so I told
many hops do you want to have in the
onion world and of course that on the
other hand here is then what you bring
up I said that the more transparency you
have in that sense and the more easy it
is to understand the better so I didn't
want to talk to you too much about
wasabi because I think that's a whole
other conversation but I would like to
push this as an idea would anybody be
interested in having this discussion
next week sort of like a philosophical
continuation or should this be much much
later once we've read many more papers I
would prefer it after what is it April
6th it's a very specific day oh why
and you probably mean April 5th the
conjoin day which is the Nexus IV
release
yes April 5th because that's the coin
join indeed as the Nexus ah be release
and whatever happens then after that I'm
going to hundred percent concentrate on
research
[Music]
yeah that's that's why I read you that
you will concentrate on research no yeah
you know I'm coding a lot and trying to
wrap up everything but of the things
with Bitcoin core actually that means -
mmm there is some constant needed for
for something in Bitcoin core in order
to properly implement it - wasabi but
constants is not reached so like maybe
maybe it kind core integration will be
delayed to further future than I hoped
previously sunny vague anymore more on
this or should we discussed the next
sessions topics that what should it be
I thought had quite a lot but Rafael go
ahead yeah I just had one thought about
topic about of picking up or different
coins for your transaction I mean if we
are actually just trying to confuse
these China analytics companies with
deep doing like mixing up with the
heuristics and all of that stuff I mean
why don't we just try to like for
example the things like pay join where
you are making the transaction look like
different that it actually is it doesn't
look like a normal payment so why don't
we just try to add these kind of options
into the wallet or why do not force the
users to do a certain thing but just
give them a lot of tips and hints why
this and that way of doing stuff would
be good for their anonymity
would just educate people already so on
that topic this is what I was I was
gonna leave out but I'll just hint at it
briefly by having users be able to
consolidate and spend and coin joint in
the same transaction
it makes things way easier for us from
the perspective of of hiding from
forensics because now the wasabi is is
just all users are are doing actions
only inside these massive coin joint
transactions as opposed to doing actions
on their own terms
sending sending funds outside of those
transactions so that would be like
revolutionary like gigantically forward
in terms of privacy absolutely I agree
you know it for the next content
implementation I would just love to have
users being able to register multiple
inputs to generate multiple outputs and
to be able to send precise amount to a
external wallet address that would then
would be I think the win for Bitcoin
privacy so we just need to figure it out
yeah sorry I was just gonna say that
definitely that what max said but you
could just add multiple inputs and get
some multiple outputs wherever you want
but that would be pretty great I mean
that would mix up a lot of different
heuristics wouldn't it I mean even as
simple as being able to to take your
mixed coins and pay someone in a wasabi
coin joint it would change everything
because it means that anyone who
receives funds anyone who spends and
what's not be conjoined how put doesn't
necessarily mean that they've ever used
wasabi and that's what that's what would
really change the game in terms of
privacy so I could literally : join into
my exchange address and that exchange
now looks like it's doing coin joints
even though it's not so it's it is so
then it becomes hard to blame someone
for having the wasabi coin joint hug
yeah I do like that idea but I just
think that that might give a little bit
of problems for the whoever receives the
coins you know if they are not aware of
these being conjoined coins and if there
is someone like flagging them I'm not
sure but I mean I like the idea but just
we should all also think about the
probable problems that comes with that I
mean for example if you are sending to
an exchange through that coin joint they
could just freeze your funds or if you
are sending to someone else and they
don't they are not actually knowing it's
gonna be from a coin joint they might
get the funds freeze I don't know
indeed whether there are there many
things to take care of you one thing
that I would like to talk about as
Chapter six
but basically just the title of it which
is at or installation and I think that
is one of the aspects for wasabi is
absolutely superb where it combines both
being technically sound right having
multiple tours identities different tour
circuits that change like every couple
seconds with new circuits while still
being incredibly user-friendly in the
sense that there is nothing in the GUI
that the user has to setup but it just
works plug and play by default for every
users the same there is nothing to
configure there's nothing to [__] up you
just start wasabi and it works and it
works on a technologically very sound
level and so I think this is the prime
example of where we want to be with
everything in the wallet I'd have
everything as technologically sound and
as user-friendly meaning no
configuration at all as the tour set up
in wasabi
okay but not much to that and then the
second thing I would like to talk about
though is Chapter seven about the Java
and on proxy and what I found very
interesting that it is a graphical user
interface that has three different and
eliminated levels low which is ready
fare which is green and high which is
blue so these I found very similar to
the wasabi bullet anonymity said shields
by the Red Cross shield the yellow
exclamation shield the green shield and
the green checkmark shield by to
indicate how much anonymity set you have
of course the the more greener the
better basically
and the second part of the comparison
just just just as a there is also
another one it's over 9000
she's that's the best don't tell them
about it but another comparison to this
mjp that I found so interesting is that
their level of anonymity depends on the
number of users so the more users use
the same entry and exit notes or
whatever they're called the higher the
anonymity so they think right and that
is the same as we have in wasabi that
the more users register their coins and
the more quantity of equal value on puts
being created to higher the anonymity
which in first glance makes a lot of
sense right the crowd is larger but then
what they talk about here in this
chapter of chat is that it is still if
you do for example in this case time
correlation you can still discover the
user ID and in the sense of wasabi will
be a bit different but if other users
[__] up or if for example you send to
your old to the same address twice right
address reuse or you leave your ex pop
or whatever happens there are still many
ways that despite having a large crowd
you that can still lead to the
anonymization and I'm not sure if
there is any way to to remedy that that
regardless the size of the crowd and
regardless how beautifully you display
that in the GUI there are still ways to
[__] it up and the user often times not
even does not even know that he's
[__] up his privacy I mean we are low
boiling it a lot I mean these odd thing
together anonymity sets because that's
what we are doing it's it's just so
incorrect it's mathematically speaking
we should be multiplying the anonymity
sets but we want to low boil it as much
as possible so we are not multiplying
them but adding them together I know so
it's like yeah you can [__] up things
but on the other hand we are trying to
balance it out in some some way even if
that's kind of incorrect and missing
because you gain more privacy than
actually it shows but you know what I
mean
is that correct or what what does the
paper says about this approach well
basically that it's very difficult right
that in the case of Trump the size of
the crowds does not matter if you can do
time correlation attacks right something
similar would be in Vasavi the size of
the anonymity set does not matter if you
do address reuse afterwards right if you
shoot yourself in the foot
then there's then you're screwed and you
know to a lesser extent also if others
shoot themselves in the foot then your
unanimity size decreases more and more
to a point where you might not need to
know that you no longer have any
anonymity set because all other users
are D anonymized already it makes a
couple of times then even if you don't
mix a couple of times only once
that the chances that most of the other
users are going to die anonymize
yourself the anonymized themselves I
don't know but that's why I recommend
people to mix twice just in case
I mean I knock this tree low but anyway
yeah and that's the that's the other
idea between weeks twice and from an an
apart in in time so mix once now and mix
once a year from now and then you can
you can be sure that the unanimity set
is like really like multiplying or
something like that
yeah that's a big argument that nowhere
and I have had because I'm of the firm
belief that when you have a coin from a
coin joint and then you remix it in the
immediate next coin joint it's barely
even feasible to call that addition of
anonymity set but but ok you can say
that it's the addition of the anonymity
set you will have participants that are
repeated quite a few that are repeated
from one to the next but as soon as you
remix from a coin joint a month ago to a
coin join today and everyone starts
doing that then you can actually make a
pretty solid argument for multiplication
or something that's even greater than
addition it might not be multiplication
but it but it could exactly more than
addition but you can make the argument
what the paper says that that's just not
useable if you have to wait months
before you can use your coins you know
it no all I would require is when a user
receives money they make sending before
they
want to spend their money they they mix
or they mix spend something of that
nature okay that's a good idea actually
yeah you know basically it's the idea
that and again to automate but as soon
as you receive it immediately afterwards
it registers for a coin join and then
the only way to spend is in a coin run
even if it's a naive unequal amount
coins on it doesn't matter even if it's
only a five part five person conjoint
doesn't really matter right anything is
better than having a two input two
output transaction for example just like
the regular spending transaction all
right are we ready to decide the next
week's topic one more thing that I would
like to bring up now in the context that
we talked about the the anonymity so
targets and bringing it back to the
conversation about against options
chapter four currently we have three
different options that the user can
choose yellow shield green shield and
exclamation point field is that is that
too many choices or or should the user
even have a choice for how much
anonymity said he should get because
again some users might just choose one
round some users might increase that to
whatever they want
what is it better to have the same level
of anonymity set target for every user
and not even be able to configure it I
mean once the feature is out that you
cannot take it out that's that's
something I know
you have a very good alternative of
course well I mean bad padlet argue from
the case that we are redesigning wasabi
with a new conjoint and a new UX I would
feel odd or okay so it's a tricky
question I don't really know the answer
to that what would you guys do I would
get rid of the term anonymity said
entirely get rid of the option and then
just have a system that's this the
lowest common denominator understand
something like you you have to mix once
and you have to mix once before you send
I don't know I mean in my opinion we are
thinking of talking about a little bit
way too small specifics and I don't
think they are even that big of a deal I
mean for example just indicating that
you can mix for example just seven
different or put seven different outputs
in a coin joint that's much more
relevant or problem than what's the
color of the shields or the unanimity
set number I mean I think those are
awesome information I think those are
pretty relevant I don't think those are
anyway like disturbing or confusing for
new users I think they are pretty great
but there's a lot of these different
things that are a bit confusing I know
that they're meant there are many quirks
on the design that that really should be
redone or just to make it more beautiful
in general yeah I don't know I just like
the current version way too much and I'm
like that don't don't you guys mess it
up so much yeah me too me too
but one other thing to consider again is
the point that especially now where the
user pays for
or please / and in the mid he said it's
it's a question of of how much is the
user willing to pay and of course with
with network level and anonymity he just
pays with his time of his computational
power but for Bitcoin anonymity he pays
for it with his money it's so that is
something to consider as well there
might be users we have you know a high
threshold for spending as much as
possible on privacy because they're
really desperately needed in quotations
again that might lead to actually them
being D anonymized but if it's clear
that this one user paid a lot and he
might be tracked and that might be a
fingerprint and only other hand other
users just want to have very light
preliminary privacy and they don't want
to pay as much and and again to get
these two things together is again
options and configurations and and
trying to reduce the footprint it's it's
very difficult because of the virus we
might have to cut our beards down to
make it not airtight anyway so guys what
do you think about what do you think
about me if I'm not if I have time then
I would cut out the wasabi conversations
from this and and and let I don't know
just just cut out you know presentations
now yeah but max aren't you worried that
our dozens of viewers are gonna be
overwhelmed there's like you mean
literally wonderful do you know when I
walk the streets now max I keep getting
accosted by people who recognized me
from YouTube it's like I can't deal with
this Fame alright guys I do have to go
pretty soon so uh no para do you want to
decide to the paper or suggest people
have may I just ask
one add one more thing about this wallet
discussion maybe just adding something
like the total percentage of or at least
the estimation about with the current
amount of participant in the next coin
join times the actual fee that goes to
the coordinator and possibly like the
actual network fee also but just give us
some kind of estimate for the user I
think that would be pretty awesome so
because in my opinion there's a lot of
these questions about how much is
actually going to pay young people like
calculating it and all that kind of
stuff yeah I agree
I'm not quite sure where to put it
obviously I cannot crowd more things
into the coin joint top because it's
already scary but this should be there
[Music]
I'll take a look around it and just give
some kind of idea anyway avi do you have
any suggestion for for the paper next
week nope okay so here are the things
heuristics on Bitcoin privacy Vicky
Cohen joins Sudoku boards Minh papers
from blockchain owner is this company's
topological analysis of the Lightning
Network I am NOT an anthro piece blocks
I design and application of blockchain
analysis platform traceability analysis
on one arrow towards information
theoretic metric for anonymity a brief
history of linear and mixed integer
programming computation okay so I'm not
going to to to talk about the - to say
these these papers again to say what
what you think would be interesting and
we will vote on them
I think last time also we we said there
would be good - now after this more
philosophical paper go into the
calculation of the value of anonymity so
that will be conjoined pseudocode that
will be Boltzmann later why I am NOT an
entropy and I think that would be an
interesting path to go down
how do we score the quality of 0.1
they've on paper I think it would be
good to start with Sadako okay coin
joins Dooku who is voting for that yeah
I second the motion
yeah I like that too okay I'm going for
that too Oh everyone is voting for that
then I guess we just got a winner Cohen
joins the Doku next week all right
so are you sure I shouldn't cut out the
wasabi stuff because it's it it should
be about the paper I mean it's not a big
deal it's like in 20 people that are
gonna watch it so not a big deal no and
I think it was actually quite valuable
to have this because I mean this was a
rather philosophical one so yeah I think
it's good to apply this more right all
right then thank you guys and next week
going against Sudoku like share and
subscribe and research so thank you bye
bye